Okay, so we have some questions and we
can get into those um or we can skip in
right into the State of the Union. What
do you want to do? Yeah, let's jump into
the State of the Union. Okay. Um
let me ask you Ted,
were you as frustrated with Democrats as
I was? I mean, we we knew we knew what
to expect from Donald Trump. We knew
that he was going to be angry and ugly
and mean-spirited. We knew he because
it's his nature and he did it on
purpose. He gets a kick out of it. But
the Democrats walked right into his
trap, right into it.
Yeah.
>> Yeah. Well, he There were several traps.
So, the traps kept getting laid. Um you
know, the most notable one where he
obviously had coordinated this with the
Republican leadership where he said,
"Please, you know, you know it's
trouble." Where it's like, "You know,
I'm going to ask a question and if you
uh agree with it, stand up and if you
don't, stay sitting down." And it's
like, "Do you Do you think that the
priorities of uh you know,
elected officials should be to
prioritize the US citizens over illegal
immigrants?"
And and and so that's a trap and he just
let it lie there.
>> And and of course [__] John Fetterman
jumps right up.
Right. The only Democrat. Right.
>> right up.
Now, the thing is I happen to agree with
the answer to that question. It's a It's
a trap, of course. It is a trap. But of
course, obviously the priority of
American elected officials should be US
citizens.
Goes without saying. But Democrats don't
know what to do in a situation like
that. They should be prepared to act as
one. Um you know, maybe all get up and
walk out at that moment. Um but they
they should have been instead of just
sitting there like basically screwed.
John, I thought the Democrats um you
know,
one of my uh Republican friends uh
exed me this morning and said, "Oh, you
know, Donald Trump kicked ass." I don't
think Donald Trump kicked ass at all.
But he said But he said, oh the
Democrats looked terrible. That's true
too. The Democrats did look terrible. Um
they just didn't know what to do John. I
mean they didn't even in in years past
they had their lame little like micro
signs that they used to have a sign up.
>> wearing the tags release the Epstein
files.
>> Right, like my news. How come you didn't
wear those when Biden was president?
Right, good question. And also why are
they like two inches across?
You know, you're on national television.
You know, the only spiciness came from
Al Green.
You know.
>> Just Al Green. And and like you know,
and I thought you know, the Democrats
just didn't seem to know what to do.
They weren't willing to be there was no
civil disobedience here. I mean you
desperately needed at some points when
he was insulting them questioning their
patriotism and their sanity calling them
crazy. At some point you need a [__]
you. And it's like
where is it? What are they so worried
about that their the sergeant at arms is
going to kick them out? Whoop-de-doo.
Watch it on TV later. What a joke. I
mean
>> Yeah, you know, yeah, first of all Al
Green
Al Green did not impress me last night
with with his big sign. The The
Democratic leadership said no signs.
You're going to get thrown out. He pulls
out this giant sign black people are not
apes. Okay.
Great. And then you get thrown out. And
so what what have you accomplished?
But also if you get thrown out get
thrown out spicily, struggle, fight
back. And he didn't. He just walked out.
He just got up and went out. I mean it's
it's all so performative. And the
American people know that.
>> sides. Both sides. I I I hated it. And
I'll tell you what, when I was in
college Reagan was president, the
country was divided, Democrats on one
side Republicans on on the other. I
enjoyed those speeches.
I enjoyed them. They were substantive.
Mhm, on both sides.
You could agree to disagree. You could
stand up for what you believed in, but
there was still decorum. And there's no
decorum on either side.
>> It's a clown show.
And I mean like it literally was a you
know the I thought it was like the the I
mean I never thought I would say that I
would see a congressional Medal of Honor
which is the highest award that a member
of the military can receive from the
civilian branch of government.
You know, it's basically like the the
the Quad de Guerre or the Legion
d'honneur in France. Like it was
degraded by this spectacle.
>> It wasn't the Congressional Medal of
Honor, was it? Yeah, it was.
>> it was the Presidential Medal of
Freedom. No. No, no, no. It's the
Congressional Medal of Honor. I looked
it up. It's the with the blue ribbon and
like Melania
Melania gave gave the Congressional
Medal of Honor to that World War II
Korea veteran.
>> brain didn't allow me to realize that
that was the Congressional Medal of
Honor. It was and it was like I I
expected Montel Williams to step out any
moment or Jerry Springer. There's like
but wait, there's more. We not the
hockey team. I'm like okay, whatever.
I thought that the
>> You're right. Oh my god, the
Congressional Medal of Honor. Right.
It's that's debased. That is a an august
like every soldier dreams maybe of being
considered for that.
It's like then the I mean and you know
99.999%
will never see one much less have one. I
mean it's it was debased. It was
depraved.
The
the the reuniting of the Venezuelan
political dissident who had been
recently freed the father with his
daughter. It's like but wait, GUESS
WHAT'S BEHIND DOOR NUMBER TWO. I mean it
was Donald Trump is a consummate
entertainer, but it really felt like the
WWE more than ever before.
It was but I thought John to me
if this moment was particularly
repugnant and and made me ashamed to be
American was when he you saw the look on
John Roberts face when he first came in
and you knew this was like
he he's a smart man. He knows what's
coming. He knows he's going to be
insulted and humiliated on national
television and yet he's there, right?
And it's horrible. It's like the kind of
[__] Saddam Hussein used to do. And then
he he he it happens. He
insults the Supreme Court, questions
their decisions, which he's already
ignored, says that he's going to
continue to ignore the Supreme Court.
Four of their four or five members are
right there. Uh-huh. Uh Barrett, Justice
Barrett, like looked looked you the look
on her face he appointed her. The look
on her face was priceless. She had this
look of like oh my [__] god. Um You
know interestingly, I'm sorry to
interrupt you.
Interestingly
the Trump appointees to the Supreme
Court
have been pretty good. That's true.
They've been surprisingly good. It's
these dinosaurs like Alito and Thomas
appointed by the moderate presidents
that are just disasters.
>> No, that's that's been it that is
interesting, John. Thank you for that
observation. Uh
But I thought I mean do you make do you
think it's as important as I do? I mean
because I've never I don't I've never
seen
In my opinion they should have gotten up
and left.
>> have. We've never had a president
that has
vocalized the words
I'm going to ignore the Supreme Court.
No. Never.
>> And and and not especially not in such a
high-profile setting. Yeah. It's a
It's a direct constitutional challenge.
It is a direct constitutional challenge,
and I thought it was appalling. And I
thought that the
you know, there was just no resistance
at all worth noting.
You know what?
>> Matina Matina makes a good point here.
It could have been worse. Boring and
lies is better than we're going to war.
And And there was
>> are going to war. There was talk about
that beforehand. Like was he Actually,
you said it, Ted, as well.
Was he going to use the the speech to
announce that we were in the midst of an
attack on Iran?
I'm sure the Iranians were expecting
that. And we'll talk about Iran,
obviously. Mhm. Glasses off, huh? John,
I I got to say I I also think
politically, domestically, um Donald
Trump really squandered an opportunity
yesterday. I mean, the Republicans are
up against the are really on the ropes
um in going into the midterms. And he
didn't lay out any plan for them. No
plan. He didn't help them at all. If
you're If you're a you know, if you're
an incumbent Republican, you're you're
very worried this morning. Um
and uh you know, his polls are in the
toilet. I mean, at 37% a president might
credibly be thinking about resigning,
not delivering a State of the Union
address. Um and that number seems to
have not found its floor yet. We may it
may continue to drop. Who knows? It
might stay steady or even go up. But
right now, but
he committed the Joe Biden mistake.
Don't Don't Don't believe your lying
bank account. The economy is roaring.
Yeah. Yeah. Roaring. Yes, he did.
People don't like that. Yeah.
They don't. I really do. And I I think
it's like it's not specifically really
about this particular speech that's
going to change minds. But if that But
that is the messaging of the of the
administration and the Republican Party.
And people are going to hear that day
after day. And what that introduces is
hopelessness. Right? I mean, literally
everything that he announced was stuff
that, you know, basically, look at what
we did. Well, we all know about
healthcare. We know that the healthcare
Trump Rx thing is lame. We know that the
Trump savings accounts are lame.
Um, you know, the American people don't
think that help is on the way. If you're
suffering, you need to either know that
help is on the way or help might be on
the way. They don't feel like that now.
I think you're right.
Yeah, I think you're right. But I want
to reiterate something that we just
said. There was no plan.
And this was essentially the only
nationally televised opportunity
between now and November
to lay out a plan that the Republicans
can run on as a party. Mhm. You know,
and watching Mike Johnson sit behind uh
Trump and just smile and nod his head
and clap. It's like, buddy,
this is on you.
You should be leading your caucus and
you're not. You're just sitting there
praying that that Jesus, you know,
delivers the best ideas to you. How's
that working out?
>> [laughter]
>> You should
I mean, if I were Mike Johnson, I'd have
Newt Gingrich living on my couch and I'd
be asking him every morning, noon, and
night how he pulled off 1994 by
nationalizing the midterms. Um, you
know, that's that's what the Republicans
should be doing and they should have a
a real plan for the workplace, a real
plan for AI, a real plan for healthcare.
Lord knows they've had 10 years to come
up with one on healthcare. Um, and they
just
I don't know if they can. I don't know
if their donors won't allow them to. I
don't really, you know, I don't know if
they're too disorganized, I don't know
if this president's too scattered.
All of the above, probably, some other
stuff I'm not thinking of, but it was I
mean, you know, we we knew it was going
to be like that. That's why I didn't
bother to make the State of the Union,
you know, when I who came up with the
with the headline for today, the main
story, cuz I knew it wouldn't be the
main story. Yeah.
>> But it's still
I mean, it's still even though you know
it's coming, it's still depressing.
Still, I want to crack on the Democrats
because they are utterly devoid of any
ideas. They are terrible. And if if
anything came out of last night,
>> [snorts]
>> it is the absolute necessity, the
immediate necessity for viable third
parties.
Right, but that's not going to happen,
at least not on the national stage.
Nope.
It's not. It's got to be, you know,
really truly I think the the model is
like the
the Farmer-Labor Party or all these
early 20th century parties, right? Like
>> the uh like the Socialist Party and so
on. You got to develop regional
strength. You've got to get some
I mean, look at Bernie Sanders, right?
He's the closest thing to a resistance
that we have. He was an independent
candidate for uh for for for mayor of
Burlington, Vermont. That's where he
started.
>> Yes. And it took a long time for him he
it took, you know, decades before he
percolated up to the national stage, but
he did. That's what you have to do. It
That's the hard work. The left in this
country doesn't want to do the hard
work. They want to have a rally, you
know, on a beautiful Sunday every 4
months. That's it. They don't want to
stand out in the rain every day.
Uh you know, and and they don't want to
build a third party from the grassroots.
They don't want to organize the working
class. They They don't They want to have
a national strike just like that, you
know, you by through Facebook groups. Um
And again,
vote for me cuz I'm not the other guy is
not a strategy. No.
Although it can be, it it works
sometimes, but then like then But then
you need but this is the problem.
You know, you look at the likes of
Chuck Schumer looked like he was not
just already dead, but dead and halfway
rotten.
>> Yeah, he
>> [laughter]
>> he was he looked like a like a
scarecrow. Like he was he was like 100
years old. He was hanging like this like
Yeah, exactly. So so sure, let's say
Trump is unpopular, the Republican at
least the Republican house is unpopular,
and so the Democrats win 15, 20, 25,
whatever seats.
And then what? They've got no no ideas.
How in the world do they intend to
govern? Well, they'll impeach And and
I'll tell you another thing.
If the Democrats do win a majority in
the house, and then they immediately
move to impeach Trump again, Mhm. they
should never win another race.
That's what they will do.
>> As punishment, they should never win
another race.
No, they're they're utterly worthless.
Um you know, they're just they they're
not they're completely incapable of
rising to the occasion. And like even
the fact that like the boycott like
Hakeem Jeffries and and Chuck Schumer
told their their you know, their
caucuses um
don't you know, hey, you can boycott or
or not.
Look, you got to all be on the same page
as a party. Either you all show up Yes.
and you all do the same thing, or you
all don't show up.
>> Yes. Which would have been very
powerful, too.
That's right. It would have.
>> they would have filled the seats anyway,
but
>> Yes. they would have. You know, it's
funny. CNN was talking beforehand about
uh
about the seats.
And I didn't realize
Well, of course, there were way fewer
seats than what they need. And so um
I didn't realize that people go there
6 hours in advance to stake out a seat.
And they'll bring like lunch and dinner
with them.
And just hold their food on their lap.
And the Democrats like 112 Democrats
didn't show up yesterday between House
members and senators.
And that's why they were able to to fill
all those seats with
the Supreme Court, the cabinet,
visitors, even the sub cabinet, all
kinds of stuff.
It's just not the way it used to be. At
all. Covered has a question for you John
pertinent to all this. Did you notice
that that disgusting slob John Fetterman
actually wore a suit last night like a
normal human being?
>> First thought in my mind like I can't
believe that idiot finally put on a
suit.
Finally.
Cuz if he feels so strongly about his
about his cheap ass hoodie and stuff,
wear the hoodie. Hypocrite. Want to
support the show with style? Go to
deprogram.live and check out our merch.
That's deprogram.live
or check out the description below.
Thanks for watching.
>> [music]